Guide to the Isaac Russell Papers, 1898-1927
Department of Special Collections
Isaac Russell Papers,
1898-1927
Special Collections M444
Russell, Isaac
8 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Gift of Mrs. Althea Strohschein and Mrs. Robert Russell, 1983 and 1985
BIOGRAPHY
Isaac Russell was born in Salt Lake City on 14 December 1879 to Samuel and Henrietta Russell. With the death of his father twelve years later, young Isaac went to live with a family friend, Charles Burton, also of Salt Lake. At the outbreak of the Spanish-American War in April 1898, he joined the Utah Volunteer Battalion. Reporting first to Camp Richmond near San Francisco, he was sent to Manila that summer. He spent the next two years in the Philippines, serving both as the editor of The American Soldier, a newspaper for the troops, and, later, as General John J. Pershing's secretary.
Shortly after returning to the United States in July 1900, Russell, traveling through Palo Alto, accidentally met David Starr Jordan, President of Stanford University. Learning of the youth's regret that he lacked the course credits necessary to attend Stanford, Jordan administered a special exam for him, and Russell was admitted that fall. While at the University, Russell strengthened his journalistic skills, editing the student publications, Quad, and Chaparral for each of his four years there.
Graduating with an AB in English in 1904, Russell returned to Salt Lake City, where he soon found employment as a reporter for the Deseret News. Whatever satisfaction he might have initially found in this job, it had all but entirely dissipated by the end of 1908. By then, Russell became disenchanted with his low salary, especially in light of the fact that he had gotten married the year before to Althea Farr, (ca. June-July 1907) and could now expect to have a growing family to support. (He and his wife did in fact have three children, two sons and a daughter.) Russell also became disillusioned with the "conservative" approach of the News. Like so many journalists of the time, he did not wish to confine his writing merely to straightforward reporting but, rather, sought to attack existing inequities and press for reform. Isaac Russell, in short, was a muckraker. Indeed, in the same year as the publication of Upton Sinclair's The Jungle (1906), Russell lauded Collier's fight against patent medicines and in the years to come wrote on several other concerns of the muckrakers: the trusts, political corruption, land fraud, and the like. These writings, of course, were submitted not to the large dailies but to magazines such as Collier's, Pearson's, and Harper's, all sympathetic to the muckrakers' aims.
Quitting the Deseret News in the spring of 1909, Russell moved to New York City, joining first the staff of the Sun, and then, a few months later, the Times. Among the major stories covered by Russell during his six-year tenure at the Times were: the sinking of the Titanic (which he was apparently the first journalist to report); the continuing aviatory efforts of the Wright brothers; and U.S. interference in Nicaragua in 1913-1914. This period also witnessed the emergence of Russell as a staunch, outspoken defender of the Mormon faith, to which he belonged. In Feb 1911 he asked Theodore Roosevelt to refute charges that as President he had negotiated secret deals with the Mormon leadership. Roosevelt's lengthy response lambasted his critic and praised the Mormons, and Russell made sure the piece was prominently published. On a less spectacular, but equally passionate level, Russell also began writing letters to editors of various newspapers in which he tried to correct their misconceptions about Mormonism, particularly in regard to polygamy.
On 1 June 1915, as a result of a supposedly inaccurate article he wrote on Amos Pinchot, Russell was fired from the Times. Shortly thereafter he joined the staff of the New York Evening Mail, becoming its city editor in 1916. During his years with the Mail, Russell continued his muckraking activities, focusing his attention in particular on conditions in the military and, above all, in the labor market. Besides writing numerous articles on U.S. Army training camps, he condemned what he perceived to be the frequent use of court-martials and the supercilious attitude of officers for the "underdog" in his criticism of low wages and poor working conditions among the country's laborers. Nor did he limit his actions to writing alone. In July 1918 he was appointed a "special field representative" for the National War Labor Board; in February 1919 he became an examiner for the Railroad Wages and Working Conditions Dept. of the U.S. Railroad Administration; and the following month he joined the American Labor Party.
In the early 1920s, Russell's professional interests came to center on two issues: Utah and food. As his correspondence with Heber Grant and George Thomas--presidents of the Church of the Latter-Day Saints and the University of Utah, respectively,--reveals, Russell believed that the leadership of both church and state was so obsessed with matters of religion and finance that it stifled independent intellectual and creative initiative. Along with this anxiety over Utah's future went a desire to commemorate her past--a desire to which Russell gave concrete expression in numerous articles and, more elaborately, in his first book, Hidden Heroes of the Rockies, published by World Book in late 1923.
Of equal, if not greater concern to Russell was the question of nutrition, about which he had been writing and lecturing at least since 1917. In 1921 he asked for--and received--the editorship of the Mail's newly-established food department; but he did not stay in that position long, for the following January, having acceded to the American Baking Institute's request that he edit its new journal, Baking Technology, he moved to Chicago, where the Institute was headquartered. In this capacity--and, indeed, in all his writings about food--Russell acted in the best muckraking tradition, berating, for example, the AMA's belittlement of nutritional science and bakers' reluctance to adopt new methods. Russell revealed his own fervently "scientific" approach to food in his second, and final book, The Romance of the Holes in the Bread (published in 1925 by the Chemical Publishing), which extols the achievements of Louis Pasteur and contains a preface by his old friend and mentor, David Starr Jordan.
Nutritional and Utahan affairs were not the only targets of Russell's often wrathful pen during these years. The electrical industry, the Wright-Curtiss patent dispute over airplanes, the move to change Mount Rainier's name to Tacoma, even the laws of the road--all received Russell's vigorous attention. In the winter of 1926-1927, he left the American Institute to edit the journal Public Relations. Only a few months after assuming this new position, however, he fell seriously ill and had to be hospitalized. But he was at home when he died, of a massive heart attack, on 7 September 1927. He was not yet forty-eight years old.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The Isaac Russell papers document the personal and professional activities of a once-noted journalist and editor. The value of the collection is not solely of a biographical nature, for a sizable portion of Russell's correspondence and writings pertains to major events, personalities, and trends of his era. On subjects as diverse as Mormonism and aviation, Progressivism and nutrition, the Russell papers cast light on significant aspects of early twentieth century American civilization.
The collection, which spans 8 linear feet, is comprised of correspondence, manuscripts, published articles and newsclippings, government and legal documents, photographs, and ephemera. The papers date from 1898-1927, the bulk having been generated between 1907 and 1927. The collection is arranged into five series
SERIES DESCRIPTION
- Personal and Biographic Information, 1898-1927
  This series contains Russell's correspondence with family members. Aside from the several letters Russell wrote to his mother and brother during his two-year stay in the Philippines (1898-1900), most of this correspondence dates from 1911. Especially revelatory of Russell's character and temperment are his frequent letters to his wife (there are none from her to him) and his correspondence with his elder brother, Samuel. Other items in this series include: documents dating from his time in the Philippines; mementos of his years at Stanford (including grade reports, English compositions, and a scrapbook); membership cards; announcements and programs of lectures featuring Russell; his 1918 income tax return; two documents attesting to his appointment to the National War Labor Board; and letters of condolence sent to his widow after his death. The series also contains two files with material about Isaac Russell: two letters from his "foster father" Charles Burton attesting to his good character, a detailed letter written by his friend Ben Rich in 1908, photocopied selections from Upton Sinclair's The Brass Check (a book which refers to Russell many times), obituary notices, and assorted notes and letters by later commentators.
- Correspondence, ca. 1909-1925
  The second series includes most of Russell's nonfamilial correspondence: with friends, foes, writers, editors, publishers, businessmen, and government officials. Being largely spread out between 1909 and 1925, with some letters dating from either side of that time span, the incoming correspondence is in a chronological sense more "balanced" than the outgoing, the vast bulk of which dates from a period of only three years (1922-1924). For this reason, the incoming and outgoing correspondence have been combined, and the whole arranged alphabetically.
  Contained in this series is a great deal of information regarding Russell's personal, professional, and intellectual concerns. With close friends like Charles Burton and B.H. Roberts, Russell would discuss such matters as his personal finances and his career. To judges, governors, and business executives, Russell often complained about various "mishaps" he had suffered, such as being arrested by a traffic cop or having his rugs misplaced by a storage company. Correspondence with Edward Bryant, Howard Driggs, and Caspar Hodgson conveys his worries and hopes surrounding the publication of Hidden Heroes. Letters exchanged with newspaper and magazine editors--including Norman Hapgood, Adolph Ochs, Mark Sullivan, John Thompson, and Richard Wood--usually focus on either of two topics: Russell's attempt to get a particular article published, or, more sweeping, his views on journalism and journalists. With other friends and acquaintances--most notably Heber Grant, Walter Monson, Joseph Smith, and John Widtsoe--Russell expostulated on contemporary Mormon and Utahan affairs. The correspondence with H.A. Barnard, Lew Bolser, G.A. Menge, Edward Rumely, and Ralph Ward illuminates another of Russell's main concerns: nutrition.
  Of special interest to students of muckrakers and Progressivism would be the correspondence between Russell and some of the leading figures of his era, including Newton Baker, Josephus Daniels, Max Eastman, David Starr Jordan, William McAdoo, George Perkins, Theodore Roosevelt, Upton Sinclair, Reed Smoot, Ida Tarbell, and Joseph Tumulty. The series also contains one or two letters from each of the following: Lewis Brandeis, Clarence Darrow, R.H. Davis, Floyd Dell, Bernard DeVoto, Frank Harris, Charles Evans Hughes, Hiram Johnson, Walter Lippman, Walter Page, John J. Pershing, Amos Pinchot, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William A. White, Leonard Wood, and Orville and Wilbur Wright.
- Writings, ca. 1905-1927
  Series III is comprised of Russell's writings: multiple drafts of Hidden Heroes of the Rockies; one draft of The Romance of the Holes in the Bread; and unpublished and untitled book-length manuscript purporting to deal with Greenwich village but in truth providing an informative and autobiographical account of Russell's thoughts on a variety of issues and people; research notes; drafts of articles, arranged alphabetically by title; published articles, arranged according to journal of publication; and newsclippings dating from 1905 to 1927 (with the majority being from the period 1916-1918). Among the myriad of topics covered in these writings are: Utah and Mormon history, food, organized charity, business and industry, labor, state and national politics, education, false labeling, the death penalty, and David Starr Jordan.
- Subject Files, ca. 1905-1927
  Contained in the fourth series are correspondence, manuscripts, published articles, newsclippings. government and legal documents. Not all the items in this series are by or pertain directly to Russell, nor does the presence of a particular subject file preclude there being other material relating to that subject in the other series. The files which are the most self-contained and which include a sizable portion of Russell's own correspondence and other writings are those dealing with aviation. Central America, electricity, Palisades Park, the Tacoma-Rainier dispute, the Titanic, and Melvin Vaniman (a dirigible manufacturer and operator). The files labeled "Mormonism"--and especially those subtitled "letters to editors"--likewise contain abundant material by Russell himself, but much is also to be found on this topic in the correspondence series; the same applies, on a lesser scale, to the files on Egypt and to the "labor troubles" subsection of "economic and labor issues." The remaining files within that latter category--as well as those on baking, farming, food, free speech, and Utah history--consist for the most part of others' writings and statements, Russell's own views on these matters to be found scattered throughout the second and third series. Other files in Series IV--those on the Community Art League and the St. Lawrence Seaway, for example--contain material found within the collection but bearing uncertain relationship to Russell. The series concludes with miscellaneous writings by others and with assorted ephemera.
- Photographs
  The final series consists of photographs of Russell, Melvin Vaniman, and other acquaintances, various types of planes, and assorted interior and outdoor scenes. The series also contains some negatives.
CONTAINER LIST
- PERSONAL AND BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION, 1898-1927
  - FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE, 1898-1926
    - Carl Beck, 1915-1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Carl Beck, 1918-1923 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Frances Beck, 1917-1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Richard W. Burton, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Althea Russell, 1907-1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Althea Russell, Aug. 1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Althea Russell, Aug.-Sept. 1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Althea Russell, Sept. 1916-July 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Althea Russell, July-Nov. 1918 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Althea Russell, Dec. 1918-Feb. 1919 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Althea Russell, Mar.-July 1919 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Althea Russell, July 1919 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Althea Russell, July-Aug. 1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Althea Russell, Aug. 1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Althea Russell, Aug.-Nov. 1919 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Althea Russell, Nov. 1919-Jan. 1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Althea Russell, Jan.-Aug. 1922 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Althea Russell, Aug. 1922-Jan. 1923 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Althea Russell, Jan. 1923-Apr. 1926 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Althea Russell, Apr.-May 1926 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Althea Russell, May 1926 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Althea Russell [daughter], 1922 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Chris [Russell?] (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Cuddy [Russell?], 1917-1923 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Cuddy [Russell?], 1925-1925 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Donald [Russell?], 1923 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Francis Joseph Russell [brother]. 1921 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Henrietta Hope Russell, 1898-1916 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Henrietta Hope Russell, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Jacob Parley Russell [brother], 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Jared Pratt Russell [brother], 1912-1922 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Lutie [Russell?], 1922 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Lutie [Russell?], 1923 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Robert Russell, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Samuel Russell [father], 1923 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Samuel Russell [brother], May-Aug. 1898 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Samuel Russell [brother], Aug.-Oct. 1898 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Samuel Russell [brother], Oct. 1898-Jan. 1900 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Samuel Russell [brother], Nov. 1911-Apr. 1917 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Samuel Russell [brother], July 1917-May 1918 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Samuel Russell [brother], May 1918-Apr. 1921 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Samuel Russell [brother], May 1921-July 1923 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Samuel Russell [brother], July 1923-Apr. 1924 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Samuel Russell [brother], July 1924-May 1927 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Sherman Smith, and his daughter Jennes, 1912-1926 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified family correspondence (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - OTHER PERSONAL PAPERS, 1898-1927
    - About Isaac Russell, 1898-1927 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - About Isaac Russell, 1920-1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Condolence letters, A-L (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Condolence letters, L-W (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Lecture announcements, 1910-1924 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Membership cards, 1903-1927 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Military service in the Philippines, 1898-1899 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous. 1916-1922. n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Stanford, alumni lists, 1923-1925 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Stanford, compositions. 1901-1904 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Stanford, memorabilia, 1901-1904 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Stanford, scrapbook, 1901-1904 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- CORRESPONDENCE, ca. 1909-1925
  - Abbot-Alsberg (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alter-Anderson, E. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, H.-Aschenberg (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Badger (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Baer-Baker, N. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Baker, R.-Baker's Review (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Balch-Beatty (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Beebe-Binns (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bishop-Boker (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bolser (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bonnell-Bryan (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bryant, Edward, May 1922-Oct. 1922 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bryant, Edward, Oct. 1922-Apr. 1923 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bryce-Burritt (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Burton, Charles S., Apr. 1911-July 1914 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Burton, Charles S., Aug. 1914-Mar. 1918 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Burton, Charles S., Mar. 1918-Apr. 1921 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Burton, Charles S., May 1921-Nov. 1922 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Burton, Charles S., Nov. 1922-Mar. 1923 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Burton, Charles S., Mar. 1923-Dec. 1923, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Burton, E.-Case (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Chamberlin-Chicago Tribune (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Christensen-Cohn (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Coleman-Collins (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Connelly (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Connelly-Coyne (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Craig-Cruger (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cullen (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cummings-Dakin (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dale-Dame (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Daniels-Davis (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dawe (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Day-Devine (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - DeVoto-Drew (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Driggs, Howard, June 1920-Sept. 1922 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Driggs, Howard, Nov. 1922-Feb. 1923 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Driggs, Howard, Mar. 1923-Oct. 1924 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Drum-Eastman (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Easton-Ewers (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Farr-Fisher (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Fitch, J. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Fitch, J.-Forman (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Fosdick-Fussell (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Gaines-Gilley (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Gleason-Glynn (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Goff, Harold, Aug. 1920-Feb. 1924 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Goff, Harold, Apr. 1924-Feb. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Goins-Goudiss (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Grant, Heber J., Feb. 1920-Feb. 1922 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Grant, Heber J., July 1922-Aug. 1923 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Grant, Heber J., Sept. 1923-Aug. 1924 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Grant, Heber J., Nov. 1924-Feb. 1926 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Grant.P.-Guthrie (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - H.B. Cushman-Hansen (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Jan. 1909-Mar. 1911 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Apr. 1911-Dec. 1911 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Jan. 1912-Dec. 1913 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Jan. 1914-Nov. 1914 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Nov. 1914-Apr. 1915 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Sept. 1912-Nov. 1922 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Nov. 1922-Nov. 1923 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Nov. 1923-Feb. 1924 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Hapgood, Norman, Feb. 1924-Sept. 1924 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Harmon-Harris (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Harrison (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Hart-Haynes (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Hayward-Hendrick (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Heney-Hix (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Hodgson, Caspar, Apr. 1921-Oct. 1923 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Hodgson, Caspar, Oct. 1923-Dec. 1923 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Hodgson, Caspar, Jan. 1924-oct. 1924 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Hodgson, Caspar, Nov. 1924-June 1925 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Hodson-Howard (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Howe-Irwin (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Irving-Jalufka (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Jamaica Storage and Warehouse, Jan. 1922-May 1923 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Jamaica Storage and Warehouse, May 1923-Nov. 1923 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Janes-Jones (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Jordan, David Starr, Jan. 1908-Apr. 1923 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Jordan, David Starr, May 1923-Feb. 1924, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Journal of the AMA-Keppel (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Kiefer-Knecht (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Knoll-Lavck (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Lawler-Light (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Lindsey-Long Island Storage Warehouses (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Love, Steven, June 1909-Feb. 1914 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Love, Steven, Feb. 1914-Mar. 1915. n.d. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Lovejoy (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Mabey-MacDonnell (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - McDowell-McKelway (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - McKeon-Marsh (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Matthews-Mellor (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Mendel-Menge (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Mercer-Mitchell, R. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mitchell, S.-Molloy (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Monson (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Morany & Company-Moskowitz (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Moyle-Natkins (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Naughtin-New York Telephone Company (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - New York Times-New York World (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Newman-Nicoll (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Nolan-Noyes (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Ochs, Adolph S., June 1915-Feb. 1917 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Ochs, Adolph S., Sept. 1921 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - O'Connor-O'Ryan (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Osborn-Palmer (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Peltsits-Pelters (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Perkins (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Pershing-Platt (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Post-Prendergast (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Pruerr-Rabb (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Rabenold, Ellwood, May 1922-Oct. 1922 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Rabenold, Ellwood, Nov. 1922-Apr. 1925 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Ray-Reynolds (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Rice-Riter (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Roberts, Brigham H., Apr. 1909-Feb. 1910 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Roberts, Brigham H., Sept. 1910-Jan. 1913 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Roberts, Brigham H., Feb. 1913-Feb. 1920 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Roberts, Brigham H., Mar. 1920-Aug. 1927 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Roberts, W.-Roosevelt. K. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Feb. 1911 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Feb. 1911-Nov. 1917 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Rosenbluth-Ruhl (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Rumely (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Rumsey-Schurman (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Sellards-Shaw (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Shedd-Sinclair, M. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Sinclair, Upton, May 1914-June 1915 (Box 7, Folder 20)